<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rox!</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 19:11:38 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 19:11:38 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>I made a little zine adventure about building skills for data analysis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/pycon_zine_print_4.25.16.pdf&quot;&gt;Go right to the zine&lt;/a&gt; (print it duplex, flipping on the long side, and then cut the pages in half horizontally. The pages should fold together in the correct order)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended &lt;a href=&quot;/community/2015/04/16/pycon.html&quot;&gt;my first PyCon&lt;/a&gt; last spring. I decided that if I were to go to that conference again, I would want to try something new that I hadn’t done the first time. I thought maybe I would like to try presenting something. A couple days before the submission deadline I discovered that they were accepting poster proposals. I threw one together for a project I’d been noodling on but wasn’t quite sure how to do, and it was accepted!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have to finish my project. The idea I had been noodling on was creating some type of fun resource for others like me who are research and data people interested in learning to program. I’ve had a really challenging time and I wanted to think more deeply about why it has been so hard, and what might make it easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to go to a prototyping workshop (&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1fVbyV4reuIX6nQv3h5WDDlh_wqJTD-pA3Se5J-si3YI/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;notes are here&lt;/a&gt;) at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opentwincities.org/events/2016/01/29/geocode-2/&quot;&gt;Geo:Code 2.0&lt;/a&gt;, a local hackathon focused on geospatial data, so I used what I learned there to put together a problem and solution statement for my project. Here it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Problem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non-programmers interested in learning programming as a tool to help them work with data need a way to identify appropriate learning resources because there’s so much out there it can be daunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Solution&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My solution is an interactive resource like an internet quiz that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collects information on what/why learner wants to learn programming, learning preferences, and current experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommends types of resources that might be helpful and ways to identify and locate them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Directs the learner to some actual example learning resources for learning Python and R&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My vision is that the tool gives you a place to start and some help to map out a path to get from where you are to where you want to be. Maybe some terms to google, some examples of types of things to look for, some guidance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read this statement to some folks at Geo:Code 2.0 as well as some data colleagues of mine to see what they thought and I refined it a little. Then I started trying to plan out the resource, but I realized that there were a lot of pieces and it was challenging to try and plan them all at once. I got stuck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was staring instead of working when I remembered that at PyCon last year, a local Montreal PyLady I met (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/b0rk&quot;&gt;Julia&lt;/a&gt; gave me a copy of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jvns.ca/blog/2015/04/14/strace-zine/&quot;&gt;technical zine she wrote about strace&lt;/a&gt;. I have no idea what strace is or why you would use it, but I love that she made a zine about it! I told her I owed her a zine, and I daydreamed about a zine exchange at PyCon for this year. I tried to write a zine about my experience at PyCon but never got very far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, this was all I needed- inspiration! I could make a zine that illustrates the problem that my project aims to address. I am still on a bumpy winding path to learning programming, and I want to create the resource that I didn’t have. What better way to start than to tell the story of my bumpy winding path!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So using my idea to create a “Choose Your Own Adventure” style thing, I made a little adventure zine about trying to build skills for data analysis. You can download the print version &lt;a href=&quot;/files/pycon_zine_print_4.25.16.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. The zine walks through each of the things I’ve tried and explores the pros and cons I’ve experienced with the options. Some of the stories are embarrassingly true and unfortunately not exaggerated (like the one where I become an organizer of a local user group!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;What I’m working on now&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharing this with anyone who’s interested, and hoping to gather feedback on two things: what challenges others have faced while trying to learn programming for data analysis, and what would be useful to go into the tool in terms of both content and structure.  I am planning to bring my zine to the Data Analysts for Social Good conference &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dogooddata.com/&quot;&gt;Do Good Data&lt;/a&gt; in Chicago, as well as a local all-women hackathon &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hackthegap.com/&quot;&gt;Hack the Gap&lt;/a&gt; here in Minneapolis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the note I include at the end of the zine, reflecting on what some of the challenges I encountered are. If you are interested, please contact me! I would love to hear from you. You can email me at john3718@umn.edu or tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/roxLjohnson&quot;&gt;@roxLjohnson&lt;/a&gt;. I hope you enjoy it! It was really fun to make :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll post an update after PyCon with what I ended up presenting at the poster session. I’m really looking forward to going to the conference with the purpose of hearing about learning tips from people who use Python all the time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;About&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many cool things you can do to obtain, clean, analyze, explore, and visualize data if you know some programming. I&amp;#39;ve been a research analyst for about five years, and actively trying to learn Python and R for data analysis for about two years. I&amp;#39;ve found it extremely challenging and I&amp;#39;ve met many others with similar experiences. This zine is based on the true story of my own learning experience and aims to highlight some of the challenges I continue to face:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not knowing where to start or what the big picture looks like; no clear view of what&amp;#39;s possible or a map of how to get there&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vast number of resources is daunting; it is difficult to find resources that are both at my skill level and relevant to what I want to learn&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not knowing what I don&amp;#39;t know- lacking the awareness that I don&amp;#39;t understand a core concept, and not being able to articulate questions or search terms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many resources are intended for people who are or want to become developers or professional programmers, which isn’t me&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t feel like I fit anywhere- other researchers may not know about programming, people who regularly work with data in Python sometimes Excel-shame me, and programmers tell me that learning Python is easy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on my experience and talking to other data people about their challenges, I decided to create a tool that will help data people start to explore the world of programming for data analysis. The tool starts with an assessment of why you want to learn programming, what your current skills are, and how you like to learn. It will then recommend ways to find relevant resources and direct you to some examples of actual resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking for stories of other data people working to learn programming, and also feedback on the development of my tool! If you are interested, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/notes/2016/04/25/zine.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/notes/2016/04/25/zine.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CycleHack at the Winter Cycling Congress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016/wcc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Winter Cycling Congress&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This winter for the first time ever, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wintercyclingcongress2016.org/&quot;&gt;Winter Cycling Congress&lt;/a&gt; (WCC)- an international exchange of ideas and strategies to get people on bikes in the winter- was scheduled to be in the US; in my hometown of Minneapolis. I don’t do a lot of work on bike stuff but  love riding my bike in all seasons so I was really curious about what such an event would be like. Since I had been involved in organizing a local &lt;a href=&quot;/community/2015/06/29/cyclehack.html&quot;&gt;CycleHack&lt;/a&gt; bike event last summer, I saw this opportunity to get myself into the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I submitted a proposal to do a poster with my colleague and CycleHack co-organizer &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LKPuffer&quot;&gt;Leah Puffer&lt;/a&gt;. The organizers accepted the proposal and asked if we would also be willing to talk about CycleHack at a roundtable session. It seemed to me like a once in a lifetime opportunity so of course we said yes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our plan for the WCC was to tell folks about CycleHack Twin Cities and potentially recruit them to help organize an event for 2016. We also wanted to spread the word about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclehack.com/&quot;&gt;CycleHack&lt;/a&gt; the global movement (since this was an international event), and tell people about the resources that the global organization and website offers to local groups interested in organizing their own CycleHack event. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016/cyclehack-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Myself and Leah at one of our roundtables&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Myself and Leah at one of our roundtables, photo by Sheldon Mains&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We knocked our goals out of the park: Our poster session and round tables were well-attended, and people were really excited about the method of “CycleHacking” to get communities involved in thinking up ideas to address barriers to cycling. I made some contacts at local bike organizations that may be interested if we do another event, and we heard some feedback on project ideas generated at CycleHack that may be useful to actually create- particularly the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclehack.com/catalogue/bicycle-rights-and-duties-spoke-card/&quot;&gt;spoke card&lt;/a&gt; that had rights and duties of a cyclist on one side and what to do in a crash on the other. People really liked that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was more interesting to me and what made the whole conference worth attending was that this year, the Congress looked at winter cycling through the lens of equity. Many of the sessions discussed groups that have been traditionally left out of cycling and cycling conversations both in Minneapolis and elsewhere, and what that means. It was also great to hear from people in those groups and not just about them from “the usual suspects”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some great conversations about the way we talk about bikes and cycling as well as winter weather, types of bikers/cyclists/people who ride bikes, and how identity can impact who becomes a person who rides a bike. This conference set a bunch of my neurons in motion, influencing how I think broadly about my recreational work organizing as well as my career as a researcher and data storyteller. I had many thoughts and discussions on language, inclusion, equity, and engagement. Here are some of those thoughts, combined with some of the take-aways from my time at those sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language is really important! There were several instances of intentional language that I found thoughtful and extremely useful. Some are about how we talk about individuals and communities, some are about the weather, all are people-focused and aim to re-frame the way we approach and understand problems, opportunities, and solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low wealth communities instead of low income communities. Income only refers to employment; we are talking about communities that are experiencing chronic long-term underinvestment and generational disparity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using “enslaved” instead of “slavery”. This was something I noticed in one of the sessions; I had heard an explanation elsewhere about bringing awareness to the people who caused and participated in slavery instead of making it sound like it was a thing that happened passively. Also, it centers enslaved people as people and not just their position in society (“slave”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Media language- I went to a session where &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Kub64&quot;&gt;Glenn Kubish&lt;/a&gt; talked about how the news vilifies winter. I don’t watch a lot of news but I recognized each and every strategy he talked about seeing on his local news in Edmonton, Alberta. Here’s the list: 
Autocorrect: the bias toward the automobile; winter is hard because it’s difficult to drive in it.
LoCalifornia: snow and cold is unnatural here! What do we do?! 
Silver Linings Playbook: “we all know the weather is bad, but there is a fun/bright side.”
Snowmanthropomorphism (my personal favorite): winter is a bad guy! He’s out to get us! Also, let’s name winter storms with human names. Then we can yell AT them! 
Weathertorializing: winter is evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in that session, Dan Patterson from Hennepin County put up a list of words he’d like to eradicate from bike vernacular:
Alternative transportation: It’s just transportation.
Amenity: he put up a picture of a chocolate fountain. We’re not talking about nice-to-haves.
Accident: crashes are avoidable and something caused it, it’s not an “accident”.
Drivers: reframe to people driving (people-first language)
Bicyclist: people biking
Pedestrian: people walking
The car did it: blaming the car erases the person who caused a problem. “Hit and killed” is passive and doesn’t emphasize that a person driving a car killed someone.
Vehicles: bikes are vehicles! If you’re talking about motor vehicles, say so.
Citizen: cities don’t have “citizens”, they have residents. This also leaves out people in a community who are not citizens.
Delay: a delay is unexpected and you can’t anticipate it, like bad weather grounding planes at an airport. Time spent at an intersection should be called waiting your turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intention&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended a workshop on how to create a skillshare presented by Low and Julia from &lt;a href=&quot;http://greaserag.org/&quot;&gt;Grease Rag Ride and Wrench&lt;/a&gt;, a women-trans-femme (WTF) bike organization. The facilitators were very intentional about creating a safer space: using everyone’s preferred gender pronouns, encouraging everyone to participate, setting some ground rules, and clearly identifying what it looked like to participate and what the expectations were. The intentional facilitation made the space overtly welcoming, instead of simply saying “all are welcome”. This is something I’m trying to learn more about because we say this for most events I’m involved in, but what does it mean? How do you show participants that this is a space for them, and actually make it a space that’s welcoming to them? These facilitators were able to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One session I attended got us talking about our identities and privileges. I found this one interesting because I’ve been moving away from an identity-focused mindset. It started to bother me that I feel that sometimes I have to “identify” as something- a programmer, a cyclist, a feminist, a scientist. Sometimes I don’t feel like I AM those things, even though I DO those things. I’ve started thinking more in terms of action and the things I do instead of what I am. That said, I think it is useful to be aware of your identity especially as others may perceive it because there are privileges associated with certain aspects of identity. For example, I am a white, middle-class, US-born, educated woman. These facts definitely influence how I move through the world and the experiences I have. I’ still thinking about this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Culture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a theme of talking about the different types of cyclists we have here in Minneapolis and also elsewhere. I talked to a woman from the Netherlands who was very confused about North American bikers when she started working with them- recreational cyclists and their spandex were completely foreign to her. And so are their bikes. Dutch bikes all come with lights, fenders, and ways to carry things, because in the Netherlands everyone rides to run errands- including taking their kids to school. In the US, we may not have access to bikes like that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the panel I mentioned on language, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BillLindeke&quot;&gt;Bill Lindeke&lt;/a&gt;
 was talking about his research on what gets new people on bikes. He brought up that one challenge is that how you interact with the city around you on a bike is completely different than in a car- you have to learn and become comfortable with that new (and more vulnerable) way. This comfort will also depend on what kind of bike you ride. When roads are designed for cars, the make/model of the car doesn’t matter. When infrastructure is designed for bikes, it matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also where the hashtag #cartesia was coined. It means “the disembodiment that is car driving”. I love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was another culture conversation going on about ways to engage groups underrepresented in bike advocacy work. This conversation was about “meeting people where they’re at” and doing the work to understand a community, how it operates, and how people in that community prefer to get involved before simply engaging them in a standard or historic way. There was also a clear message about the need to compensate people for their expertise and respecting the value of their experiences. Lastly, there was a call to action to tell it like it is and name problems instead of tiptoeing around them with coded language. This includes acknowledging racism and racial disparities exist, that they and the systems that hold them up are intentional, and that to change them we also need to be intentional and take action for racial justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016/wcc3-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Winter Cycling Congress&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/community/2016/02/04/WCC.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/community/2016/02/04/WCC.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>community</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Humphrey School Career Exploration Twin Cities Trip: 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of my role on the Student Relations Committee of the Humphrey School Alumni Board, I helped organize the Career Exploration Trip: Twin Cities again this year. This is my second time being involved with this trip (&lt;a href=&quot;/community/2015/01/15/HHH-CET.html&quot;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; we won an award!). This year, instead of categorizing the panels by sector like we did last year (government, non-profit, private), we decided to use topics: housing, communications, and society. We also decided that committee members would moderate the panels; I moderated the society panel. Our goals for the trip are for current students to hear from alumni about their career path from graduation to their current job, for students to network with alums and each other, and for alumni to maintain a connection to the school by participating in an event. I think it’s also a fun opportunity for alums to get to know each other and reflect on their Humphrey School experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole day was a fun trip for me. The alumni that participated all did really different jobs but there were some great kernels of wisdom that emerged. I think everyone had a fun time getting together to talk about their path from the Humphrey School to what they’re doing now. After the society panel, since we were at Met Council, several other Humphrey alums who work there came for a meet and greet to chat with students. I would love to see this happen again because a day of three consecutive panels gets to be monotonous and I think the students really enjoyed the opportunity to get up, mill around, and chat one-on-one or in small groups with alumni in a more informal setting. Since each alum introduced themselves briefly, students could target individual people they wanted to meet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended the day with a reception put together by the Alumni Relations Committee of the Alumni Board, where we could relax, eat some delicious food, and continue networking over drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the full panelist line-up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Housing, Community Development, &amp;amp; Sustainable Cities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andriana Abariotes, Executive Director Twin Cities Local Initiatives Support Corp. (MA ’95)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paul Fate, Principal PFate and Associates (M-Plan ’89)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryan Peterson, Development Director, Northside Achievement Zone (MPA ’14)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David White, Public Funding, Grants, and Government Relations, Habitat for Humanity (MURP ‘13)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016/housing-panel-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Housing Panel&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Housing Panel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the Word Out: Communications, Public Affairs and Government Relations&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Matt Swenson, Press Secretary &amp;amp; Senior Communications Advisor for Governor Mark Dayton (MPP ’09)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scott Beutel, Legislative &amp;amp; Public Affairs Liaison at MN Department of Human Rights (MPP ’11)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kristin Beckmann, Deputy Mayor of the City of St. Paul (MPA ’00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abou Amara. R, Advisor to the Minority Leader, Minnesota House of Representatives (MPP ‘12)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016/tpt-comms-panel-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Communications Panel&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Communications Panel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Policy in Society: Diverse ways Humphrey grads make an impact&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bill Bushey, Lead Organizer at Open Twin Cities and Software Engineer at GovDelivery (MS-STEP ’11)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ambreasha Frazier, Director of Student &amp;amp; Recent Alumni Relations at University of Minnesota Alumni Association (MS-STEP ‘12)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zachary Hylton, Planning and Evaluation Analyst at Ramsey County Human Services (MDP ’14)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016/met-council-panel-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Society Panel&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Society Panel, photo by Madeline Welter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet and greet with Met Council Humphrey Alumni&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cole Hiniker, Planning Analyst, Metropolitan Transportation Services (MURP ‘09)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raya Esmaeili, Planner (MURP ‘11)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Akua Asare, Program Evaluation and Audit (MPP ‘15)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Angela Torres, Senior Planner (MURP ‘09)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steve Peterson, Planning Analyst, Metropolitan Transportation Services (MURP ‘07)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2016/met-council-meet-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Meet and Greet&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meet and Greet, photo by Madeline Welter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the take-aways that I pulled out from the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commit to learning, and seek out learning opportunities. These could be through your job or other professional opportunities, formal class experiences, or they can be seeking out ways to learn new skills and information on your own. There are tons of resources out there (Meetups, online classes, tutorials, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think critically. Step away periodically to both recharge and to think big picture about where you are going and whether you are on the path to that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learn the business side and what’s important to decision makers- good stewardship of scarce resources is increasingly important.
It’s important to really understand the system in which you work, whether that’s your sector, field, organization, market, whatever. Not only the “official” way that things work, but also the politics, how decisions get made and by whom, what individual and organizational roles are within the system.You need to understand power dynamics, institutional structure, organizational culture, and human interaction. This will help you not only be more effective but avoid looking foolish and losing credibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good mentors are important: seek out those who can teach you things. Whether it’s a formal or informal mentor relationship or whether you even call it “being mentored”. This could be as simple as seeking a specific skill from a person you know has that skill, or asking for a meeting that’s similar to an informational interview with someone who has knowledge you are interested to learn. Talk to people about their career paths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Network! No but really, when you get opportunities, take them. Content and experience are important, but so are relationships.
Be able to deliver a value-specific, tangible contribution using your skill set, knowledge, and experience. Then, have a couple great projects you’ve done that you can talk about clearly and concisely where you have been able to do this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone involved: the panelists, alums at the meet and greet, both the Student and Alumni Relations Committees of the Alumni Board (particularly Ambreasha Fraizer for stepping in as a panelist due to a last-minute cancellation), Habitat for Humanity, TPT, and Met Council for graciously hosting us, Humphrey School staff Courtney Barrette, Jen Guyer-Wood, Jane Vega, and Martha Krohn, and to the students, who made it through an entire day of panel discussions. What a great event!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/community/2016/01/14/CET-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/community/2016/01/14/CET-2016.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>community</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Launch! Welcome to my Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This project has been a long time coming. I wanted to have a place to put all the fun stuff I have been working on, both so that I remember what I did and so that I can share it. After many, many hours, here it is! It&amp;#39;s still very much a work in progress, but I think it&amp;#39;s a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a few projects this past year that I think are really exciting. Here are my picks for top five posts from 2015:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/projects/2015/12/25/PHMSA-part2.html&quot;&gt;PHMSA Data Analysis Part 2&lt;/a&gt;: I did my first data analysis project in R! I have been dreaming about doing this project for two years, and the pieces finally fell into place. I&amp;#39;m looking forward to working on this project more next year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/community/2015/06/29/cyclehack.html&quot;&gt;CycleHack Twin Cities&lt;/a&gt;: I was part of a team that put together an amazing local event as part of an international movement to reduce barriers to cycling. I even got to make an LED project at the Hack Factory! Stay tuned, because my co-organizer Leah and I will be presenting CycleHack Twin Cities at the Winter Cycling Congress here in Minneapolis in February 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/community/2015/04/16/pycon.html&quot;&gt;PyCon&lt;/a&gt;: I received financial aid to attend PyCon in Montreal, so I went to my first big programming conference. It was overwhelming but I met some great people and was really excited that so many sessions focused on culture, diversity, and the &amp;quot;people&amp;quot; side of technology.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/community/2015/03/07/D3.html&quot;&gt;Data Cubed Installfest&lt;/a&gt;: I led the charge of planning and hosting a pre-event for a one-day data conference to help people learn Python and R so they could go to the event ready to use the tools being presented. It was humbling to have such incredible, knowlegable volunteers, and great to hear from attendees that it was exciting and helpful to have this resource.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/projects/2015/02/13/pyladies_galentine.html&quot;&gt;PyLadies Galentine&lt;/a&gt;: I finished my first personal programming project using Python! I used what I learned in an online class to make my own project, which was both challenging and rewarding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been a great year, I&amp;#39;m excited about what I&amp;#39;ve got planned for 2016, and I&amp;#39;m sure more fun stuff that I can&amp;#39;t even imagine right now will come up too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this isn&amp;#39;t a blog and there are no comments, if you want to connect you can hit me up on social media! I&amp;#39;d love to hear what everyone else is doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/notes/2015/12/29/launch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/notes/2015/12/29/launch.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>notes</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Natural Gas Distribution State Pipeline Analysis PART 2: R for Summary Tables</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I have now done a similar analysis for two states using the same &lt;a href=&quot;http://phmsa.dot.gov/portal/site/PHMSA/menuitem.6f23687cf7b00b0f22e4c6962d9c8789/?vgnextoid=a872dfa122a1d110VgnVCM1000009ed07898RCRD&amp;amp;vgnextchannel=3430fb649a2dc110VgnVCM1000009ed07898RCRD&amp;amp;vgnextfmt=print&quot;&gt;data set&lt;/a&gt; from the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Administration (PHMSA), I figured that for the third state we&amp;#39;re working in, I would try to do the same analysis using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.r-project.org/&quot;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt;  so I could automate the process- enabling us to select any state and get the numbers we wanted. My goal was to create an R script that would take input from the user for the year and state they wanted and would create an Excel spreadsheet with the summary tables for all the numbers we want summarized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by playing around in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rstudio.com/&quot;&gt;RStudio&lt;/a&gt; to see if I could read in my data- which I had to open in Excel and re-save as a csv- and then try to play around with the code to start doing the things I did in Excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took an R class on Coursera a couple years ago, but it was very challenging and I didn&amp;#39;t remember much from it so I didn&amp;#39;t get very far. Luckily my friend Alison &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/linkalis&quot;&gt;@linkalis&lt;/a&gt; is good at data analysis in R and happy to share her vast knowledge. We met up for coffee and I walked her through my previous analysis, explaining what I was hoping to do. She hooked me up with some basics- she showed me the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cran.rstudio.com/web/packages/dplyr/vignettes/introduction.html&quot;&gt;dplyr&lt;/a&gt; library and how to use it, and she made me an R script with examples of some of the things I described I&amp;#39;d want to do. I took it and ran. Thanks Alison!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Step One: Think Through the Goal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at the analysis I had done using Excel to pull together some summary tables. I drew out what tables I wanted to get a clear idea of what I wanted to create and what data I would need to pull together. I wanted nine tables: number of state pipeline operators, total state main pipeline mileage, total state number of services,  pipeline mileage by operator, services by operator, mileage of main pipelines made from leak-prone materials by operator, number of services made from leak-prone pipelines by operator, number of leaks in main pipeline by operator, number of leaks in services by operator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Step Two: Some Clean-Up and Formatting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started used the code in the sample script to figure out how to create the tables. There were a few munging tasks that needed to be figured out to clean up my tables:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The STOP field, which is used to identify the state in which the operator is operating the pipelines covered in the data set, had to be read in as a character so that I could use a filter. The R default was to read it in as a factor variable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were some extra rows that read in as NAs, so I incorporated some NA removal using the unique ID for each operator: &lt;code&gt;filter(!is.na(OPERATOR_ID)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once I had my summary tables, I removed the rows where all the entries in the columns we were interested in were 0&amp;#39;s since I knew from looking at the tables in Excel that many operators did not have any miles of pipeline made of the materials we were looking at: &lt;code&gt;filter(OP_TOTAL!=0)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To order the table with the largest number at the top (we&amp;#39;re interested in the largest numbers), I used &lt;code&gt;arrange(desc(OP_TOTAL))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Step Three: Get the Code to Make the Tables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start making the tables:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I assigned some global variables for year and state to use as placeholders that would later become user input. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To read in the data, I used read.csv: &lt;code&gt;gasdata_full &amp;lt;- read.csv(&amp;quot;annual_gas_distribution_2014.csv&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To make a table with a ubset of the fields available, I call those fields by their headers. Here, I include the NA removal and then filter by state (in this case, Indiana), and create a table that shows mileage of main pipeline made of unprotected bare steel, unprotected coated steel, cathodically protected bare steel, and cast iron for each operator. Doing this in dplyr allowed me to string all those operations together using the %&amp;gt;% command: &lt;code&gt;in_main_materials_wide &amp;lt;- gasdata_full %&amp;gt;% filter(!is.na(OPERATOR_ID) &amp;amp; STOP==&amp;quot;IN&amp;quot;) %&amp;gt;% select(OPERATOR_NAME, OPERATOR_ID, STOP, MMILES_STEEL_UNP_BARE, MMILES_STEEL_UNP_COATED, MMILES_STEEL_CP_BARE, MMILES_CI)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next I wanted to create a new field that is a summary of other fields; this example is the sum of all leak prone pipeline mileage that includes all four individual categories. I used &amp;#39;group by&amp;#39; in dplyr to select entries by Operator Name and use &amp;#39;mutate&amp;#39; to add a column to the table that would be the calculated sum of all the pipeline materials we&amp;#39;re looking at: &lt;code&gt;materials_summary &amp;lt;- materials %&amp;gt;% group_by(OPERATOR_NAME) %&amp;gt;% mutate(OP_TOTAL = sum(MMILES_STEEL_UNP_BARE, MMILES_STEEL_UNP_COATED, MMILES_STEEL_CP_BARE, MMILES_CI))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenge: using &amp;#39;arrange&amp;#39; to sort the data by a total that was calculated using &amp;#39;group by&amp;#39; in dplyr didn&amp;#39;t work. When I googled it, I found this &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/26555297/dplyr-arrange-a-grouped-df-by-group-variable-not-working&quot;&gt;resource&lt;/a&gt; on Stack Overflow that suggested that I had to ungroup the data to sort it. It worked! 
&lt;code&gt;materials_summary &amp;lt;- materials_summary %&amp;gt;% ungroup() %&amp;gt;% filter(OP_TOTAL!=0) %&amp;gt;% arrange(desc(OP_TOTAL))&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Step Four: Put the Code into Functions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I began thinking about how to use my code in functions, I realized I had to make a cognitive jump from simply manipulating data frames to creating and assigning output of a function to a variable. Conceptually I struggled with making functions because I didn&amp;#39;t understand how to &amp;quot;put something into&amp;quot; the function, especially since I started without using any arguments. Eventually I understood that calling the function and assigning that call to a variable (even if there are no arguments) will create my table, which has the name of the variable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much of my analysis gets repeated, because it gets done for both main pipeline and services. I had this tendency to want to generate more than one value in output, which you can&amp;#39;t do in R, and then I realized I could use arguments here for either pipeline main or services. So I set up an if, else if in my functions that would allow me to run the same function for main and then services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s an example of the summary for total number of miles of main pipeline and total number of services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;# table2 is a summary of total mileage of pipe (main and services) by operator
table2 &amp;lt;- function(pipe){
  if (pipe == &amp;quot;main&amp;quot;){
    summary &amp;lt;- gasdata_full %&amp;gt;% filter(STOP== state) %&amp;gt;% select(OPERATOR_NAME, OPERATOR_ID, STOP, MMILES_TOTAL)
    summary &amp;lt;- arrange(summary, desc(MMILES_TOTAL))
  } else if ( pipe == &amp;quot;services&amp;quot;) {
    summary &amp;lt;- gasdata_full %&amp;gt;% filter(STOP== state) %&amp;gt;% select(OPERATOR_NAME, OPERATOR_ID, STOP, NUM_SRVCS_TOTAL)
    summary &amp;lt;- arrange(summary, desc(NUM_SRVCS_TOTAL))
  }
  return(summary)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To call the functions with their arguments and assign them- here&amp;#39;s an example showing the tables created using the function above: one for mileage of main pipeline, and another for number of services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;Total_Main_Mileage &amp;lt;- table2(&amp;quot;main&amp;quot;)
Total_Services_Mileage &amp;lt;- table2(&amp;quot;services&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Step Five: Tie the Functions Together and Write Output&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I had all my functions written to generate the tables I wanted, I had to write a script that would create the tables and write them to an Excel file. I had to call the functions, for those with arguments I called them once for each argument, and assign the output to a set of variables. Then I wanted to write each of those tables to a different worksheet in an Excel workbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seemed tricky, so naturally I googled that too. Luckily, someone had already done this exact thing! Over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://statmethods.wordpress.com/2014/06/19/quickly-export-multiple-r-objects-to-an-excel-workbook/&quot;&gt;statMethodsblog&lt;/a&gt;, there was a nice function that was created using the xlsx library that did just what I wanted to do. I copied the function and used it to write my tables to an Excel file. The function takes the names of the tables and uses them to name the worksheets in the workbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used another little bit of code to generate the name of the workbook based on the year and state inputed by the user: &lt;code&gt;wkbk_name &amp;lt;- paste(state, &amp;quot;_&amp;quot;, year, &amp;quot;.xlsx&amp;quot;, sep =&amp;quot;&amp;quot;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last part was figuring out how to allow the user to input the year and state they choose. I wrote a couple small functions using &amp;#39;read lines&amp;#39; funtion; here is the one for year: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot; data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;readlines_year &amp;lt;- function() { 
  year &amp;lt;- readline(prompt=&amp;quot;Enter a four digit year (ex: 2013): &amp;quot;)
  return(year)
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another challenge: I programmed this on my work laptop, and then tried to run it on my personal laptop and I got a Java error. Because the xlsx library uses Java, to run the R script you need an updated version of Java. Go figure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I checked the summary numbers against the analysis I had done using Excel and Tableau. They were the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Like Magic&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once everything was put together, I can simply run the R script, enter the year and the state I want at the prompts, and an Excel workbook with the nine summary tables is created in my working directory. Magical! In the future, I&amp;#39;d like to keep working with this data set and look at some of these numbers over time (the data sets go back to the 1970s) or look at state comparisons. I have also started working on plotting this data using R. Stay tuned for more on this project!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bonus: Transforming Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I talked about in Part 1, one of the tasks that I did to make the stacked bar charts in Tableau was to take data in the wide form and transform it to the long form. Alison also showed me how to do this using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/reshape2/index.html&quot;&gt;reshape2&lt;/a&gt; library in R. But more about that in a later part of the project, when I work on plotting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/2015/12/07/PHMSA_part1.html&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; of this project&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/projects/2015/12/25/PHMSA-part2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/projects/2015/12/25/PHMSA-part2.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Natural Gas Distribution State Pipeline Analysis PART 1: Excel and Tableau Public</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The BlueGreen Alliance campaign &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bluegreenalliance.org/news/publications/NaturalGas_BiFold_R8_HighRes.pdf&quot;&gt;Repairing our Cities Aging Pipelines (RECAP)&lt;/a&gt; aims “to accelerate the repair and replacement of this network to create hundreds of thousands additional jobs while addressing the urgent threat of climate change.” This is part of the BGA Clean Energy Initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked on a couple projects looking at the mileage of leak-prone distribution pipelines and causes of leaks in two states, Minnesota and Indiana. My job was to summarize the &lt;a href=&quot;http://phmsa.dot.gov/portal/site/PHMSA/menuitem.6f23687cf7b00b0f22e4c6962d9c8789/?vgnextoid=a872dfa122a1d110VgnVCM1000009ed07898RCRD&amp;amp;vgnextchannel=3430fb649a2dc110VgnVCM1000009ed07898RCRD&amp;amp;vgnextfmt=print&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt; collected on distribution pipelines by the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA) for each of the states. This data is collected from each pipeline operator and provides the number of miles of pipeline by material as well as number of leaks by cause. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I put together the summaries that showed a snapshot of the distribution pipeline system in the state, we would add it to a handout that also included information about the broader state of distribution pipeline systems including nation-wide numbers on leak-prone pipelines and jobs numbers. We then used this handout to start a conversation with stakeholders including front line gas workers, environmentalists, and the community. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discovered that this was an important step because the data only show part of the picture. For example, in Minnesota we learned that leak detection numbers for at least one utility were increasing because they had recently piloted a new leak detection technology that was able to find smaller leaks. We learned from talking to gas workers that some utilities are proactive with efforts to decrease leaks in their systems, and others are more reactive and respond to leaks after the fact. It also became clear that there are nation-wide concerns about the aging workforce in gas workers, training, and low-quality work being done by subcontractors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See the BlueGreen Alliance final reports for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bluegreenalliance.org/news/latest/minnesota-natural-gas-distribution-pipeline-project&quot;&gt;Minnesota&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bluegreenalliance.org/news/publications/taking-stock-opportunities-and-challenges-in-indianas-natural-gas-distribution-system&quot;&gt;Indiana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Preparing The Summaries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To obtain the summary statistics for a useful conversation, These are the steps I took. Note that this is an exploratory analysis that was done in order to start a conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Step 0: Look at Data&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I downloaded the data to see what was available to us. This particular data set comes with documentation that is a copy of the form that gas operators must submit yearly to PHMSA, and the answers are the field names. There about 230 columns (questions asked), and more than 1,600 operators nationally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Part of the form that operators are required to fill out&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/phmsa_documentation.png&quot; alt=&quot;Documentation for PHMSA data set&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The columns I was interested in were:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Operator name&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;State in which the operator is operating (which I discovered can be different from the company address and HQ address)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mileage of leak prone materials, which include four materials: Unprotected Bare Steel, Unprotected Coated Steel, Cathodically Protected Bare Steel, and Cast/Wrought Iron&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of leaks by cause; causes are categorized as Corrosion, Natural Forces, Excavation Damage, Other Outside Force Damage, Material or Welds, Equipment, Incorrect Operations, and Other&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These numbers are provided for each operator, both for mains (pipelines from the distribution center throughout a city) and services (smaller pipelines from streets to a home or business). There is additional information about the age and size of the pipelines that I haven&amp;#39;t used yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent quite a bit of time looking at the copy of the form, and then looking at the columns of interest in Excel. There were a lot of zeros- many of the operators in both Minnesota and Indiana had 0 miles of leak prone pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that what I wanted to create was a stacked bar chart that showed the total mileage of each of the four leak prone pipeline materials color-coded by operator so we could see which operators had the most of those pipelines. I would create four bars for mains, and four for services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For leaks, I would do something similar: create a stacked bar chart that showed total number of leaks for each cause color-coded by operator so we could see which operators had the most leaks as well as which of the causes caused the most leaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I knew what I was looking for and what I wanted to do, I could take map out the steps for the exploratory analysis I wanted to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Step One: Get Data&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download a clean copy of the data from PHMSA, in an Excel spreadsheet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Step Two: Filter&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filter the data to get only the state and pipeline information we want: I was working in Excel, so I used the Filter and then copied the records for the state I wanted and put it in a new tab. Then I would highlight the columns I was interested in- about 13 of the 231.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/IN_gas_excel.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Data in Excel spreadsheet&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Step Three: Reformat&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reformat the data to create a stacked bar chart: I learned that to create a stacked bar chart, the data needs to be transformed from the wide form to the long form. I decided to first get rid of all the records that had all zeroes for the leak prone pipeline materials, and then manually reformat the data to what I needed (at this point I definitely knew there was a better way but I had a deadline). I created more tabs to hold the reformatted data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wide Form&lt;/em&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/IN_materials_wide.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Wide form&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Long Form&lt;/em&gt;
 &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/IN_materials_long.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Long form&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Step Four: Plot&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upload the reformatted data into &lt;a href=&quot;https://public.tableau.com/s/&quot;&gt;Tableau Public&lt;/a&gt; to make a stacked bar chart: I decided to try out Tableau Public because it allowed me to create interactive visualizations on the web without knowing any Javascript. For example, there are tooltips that allow you to see what a specific part of the chart represents. For the exploratory purposes of this analysis, I thought that was useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/IN_tableau.png&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked bar chart in Tableau: Pipeline materials with tooltips&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/IN_tableau2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked bar chart in Tableau: Pipeline leaks with tooltips&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://public.tableau.com/views/INNaturalGasDistributionPipelines/INLeaksandLeakProneMaterials?:embed=y&amp;amp;:display_count=yes&amp;amp;:showTabs=y&quot;&gt;See this dashboard on Tableau Public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This methodology got the job done and allowed us to explore the data visually in an online dashboard. Now that I’m more familiar with the data and what we’re looking at, I have thoughts on how to make this process better for this analysis, and also some fun ideas for a more interesting future analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’re working on another state over the next year, so I have the opportunity to try a different method. I’m attempting to do the filtering and reformatting using the statistical software &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.r-project.org/&quot;&gt;R&lt;/a&gt; to make tables of the variables that interest us, and some summaries of them (totals, counts, etc.). With this method, once I do one state, I could easily do them all! So much better!! I could still put these tables into Tableau Public if I wanted graphs. Or I could try out &lt;a href=&quot;https://plot.ly/&quot;&gt;Plotly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or, I am also hoping to learn how to make static charts directly in R, bypassing Tableau Public. If I can get charts that tell the same story that I can get in Tableau, I can also automate this process and save a bunch of work re-learning how to use the newer version of Tableau Public and formatting a dashboard. I suspect that some user testing could help me figure out what the most useful details to highlight are and then maybe I don’t need the Tableau Public functionality. Maybe I could even start to make explanatory graphs!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also have some ideas for additional exploratory analysis using more of the data- the data set is nation-wide, which means I could do state comparisons of things. The data set is also available yearly since 1970, so I could do a time series analysis and look at rates of replacement for leak-prone pipelines over time. I’m also attempting this in R.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One challenge for me is that I have a hard time estimating how long it will take me to learn something new, especially if it&amp;#39;s fairly unknown to me. Without this estimate I can&amp;#39;t really determine if it would save time to learn another way now, like doing the analysis in R, or if it makes more sense to muddle through the way I already know just to get it done and move on. On the other hand, I can easily fall into the trap of &amp;quot;I have to learn this really complicated tool to do this relatively simple task that I could have done another way&amp;quot;, just because I want to learn the tool. Sometimes it depends on what my other workload is, and also what I think I might use the tool for in the future. When I heard we might want to do more than one state at a time or look at national data, I knew it was time to make the investment to learn a better way. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/2015/12/07/PHMSA_part1.html&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; of this project&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/projects/2015/12/07/PHMSA_part1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/projects/2015/12/07/PHMSA_part1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CycleHack Twin Cities</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/HF_RD.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Start of Hack Day&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Start of the hack day, photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/robfargo&quot;&gt;Rob Davis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday June 20th was the first annual Twin Cities CycleHack event. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclehack.com&quot;&gt;CycleHack&lt;/a&gt; started in 2014 in Glasgow, Scotland 
and this year it has become an international effort to make the world more sustainable through reducing the barriers to cycling. 
The inspiration for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclehacktc.com&quot;&gt;CycleHack Twin Cities&lt;/a&gt; began with a visit from one of the Glasgow founders, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclehack.com/the-team/&quot;&gt;Johanna Holtan&lt;/a&gt;. 
She came and talked at an &lt;a href=&quot;http://bikeablejo.com/2014/08/27/twin-cities-cycling/&quot;&gt;Open Twin Cities meetup&lt;/a&gt; about what they had done in 
Scotland, and the idea was born to do a CycleHack here in Minneapolis. Which, by the way, is currently the only US city to make it into the top 
20 in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://copenhagenize.eu/index/18_minneapolis.html&quot;&gt;Copenhagenize Index&lt;/a&gt; of bike friendly cities around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To kick off our CycleHack, we started with some ideation to figure out what keeps people from riding bikes here in the 
Twin Cities, brainstormed ways to address those issues, and then we had a full hack day at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tcmaker.org/blog/&quot;&gt;Hack Factory&lt;/a&gt; 
where we worked on some hacks to address the things we identified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the hack day, we had several groups create some incredible projects! For more pictures and stories, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cyclehacktc&quot;&gt;@CycleHackTC&lt;/a&gt; or our hashtag &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hashtag/cyclehacktc?src=hash&quot;&gt;#CycleHackTC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn Signal Backpack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the barriers identified was the concern that drivers don&amp;#39;t see cyclists or don&amp;#39;t know what they plan to do. This group prototyped an LED 
turn signal that would be placed in a mesh pocket on the outside of your backpack, so that drivers behind you could see when you plan 
to turn. It also has a signal for stop. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/zzolo/signal&quot;&gt;Source code for Signal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/turn_signal_backpack.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Turn Signal Backpack project&quot;&gt; 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/turn_signal_backpack_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Turn Signal Backpack project&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zzolo&quot;&gt;Alan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peterjschwarz&quot;&gt;Peter&lt;/a&gt;. Photos by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/peterjschwarz&quot;&gt;Peter Schwarz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jmkeuning&quot;&gt;James Keuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bikeable.io&quot;&gt;bikable.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One group was interested in finding a better way for cyclists to choose routes using data that shows where cyclists actually ride. The 
thought was that Google Maps will give you a bike route, but won&amp;#39;t tell you if a road is in poor condition or has heavy car traffic.
The group used bike trip data from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/local&quot;&gt;Strava&lt;/a&gt;, a way for users to upload comments or recommendations, 
and they added some collision data from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.minneapolismn.gov/www/groups/public/@publicworks/documents/images/wcms1p-102346.pdf&quot;&gt;ten year study from the city of Minneapolis on vehicle/bike collisions.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/bikeable.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bikeable.io Presentation&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/anton612&quot;&gt;Anton&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/experimatt&quot;&gt;Matt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jdaltsalt&quot;&gt;Jacob&lt;/a&gt;, Dan.
Second photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jmkeuning&quot;&gt;James Keuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bikes on Buses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wbushey&quot;&gt;Bill&lt;/a&gt; worked on thinking through how it might work to collect data on whether bike racks on Metro Transit buses were available or in use. 
Starting with the physical question of how a sensor could be used to determine if bikes were already on the bus, he then considered 
how to get the data to transit users with bikes and how the system could get set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/bill_bus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bikes on Buses&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wbushey&quot;&gt;Bill&lt;/a&gt; discussing how the bureaucracy might deal with this technical solution 
to the problem, second photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jmkeuning&quot;&gt;James Keuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bike Clutch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of us organizers (myself included) decided an hour before the end of hack day that we wanted to hack something, so we considered when you 
want to go out but don&amp;#39;t want to take a bag and you need to carry your phone, wallet, and keys. We recruited another team member and used 
a sewing machine to create a little clutch that we call the bike brand bike clutch that attaches to the front of your handlebars 
with velcro. It also has the word &amp;quot;bike&amp;quot; (hence the bike brand) on it, and the dot over the &amp;quot;i&amp;quot; is an LED, so it&amp;#39;s also a headlight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/bike_clutch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bike Brand Bike Clutch&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/roxljohnson&quot;&gt;Roxanne&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LKPuffer&quot;&gt;Leah&lt;/a&gt;; not shown: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cre8ivecubed&quot;&gt;Kelly&lt;/a&gt;.
Second photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jmkeuning&quot;&gt;James Keuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoke Card&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This group was working on the problem that not knowing your rights or the law might keep people from biking, so they prototyped a spoke card 
that reminds cyclists of their rights and responsibilities on one side, and has a checklist on the other side with 
the appropriate steps if they are in an accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/spoke_card_full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cyclists&amp;#39; Rights and what to do in an accident&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/spoke_card_team_jk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cyclists&amp;#39; Rights team&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team: Marijke, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jmkeuning&quot;&gt;James&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turn Signal Helmet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One team had people who had to leave early so they didn&amp;#39;t present, but they worked on LEDs embedded in a bike helmet with programmed controls 
to create turn signals. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobypicture.com/user/gelicia/view/18234077&quot;&gt;Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/turn_signal_team.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Helmet Turn Signal team&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cre8ivecubed&quot;&gt;Kelly&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gelicia&quot;&gt;Kristina&lt;/a&gt;, Rachel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were other projects worked on by folks that couldn&amp;#39;t stay; some of them were uploaded to the 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclehack.com/location/minneapolis/&quot;&gt;global CycleHack Catalogue&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hack Factory was an amazing donated space for our first CycleHack. They had equipment and tools galore (including a laser cutter 
for trained members to use), and everyone there was open and helpful. They were gracious hosts with &amp;quot;anything goes&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;figure it out&amp;quot; attitudes. 
We had materials donated by In the Heart of the Beast Theater, Ax-Man Surplus, and numerous friends and family so that people had all kinds of 
things to use for hacks, which really set the tone for thinking outside the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ci.minneapolis.mn.us/bicycles/bike-box&quot;&gt;(bike) box&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ideation process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent some time before the hack day brainstorming barriers to cycling and ideating hacks that would address the barriers we came up with. 
We asked folks when they registered to let us know if they had ideas to hack on, and we also had an Ideascale for people to post ideas and 
also vote on other ideas that were posted. We tabled at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://makerfairemsp.com/&quot;&gt;Twin Cities Maker Faire&lt;/a&gt;, where we asked people to 
think of any issues that may keep people from choosing to ride their bike. We wrote the barriers on index cards, and sorted them into six 
categories of things we could hack: the bike, the environment, the cyclist, clothing, navigation, and culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/ideation_full.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ideation images&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brainstormed barriers, ideas to address the barriers, and suggestions for hacks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday evening before the hack day, we did an ideation bike ride around the neighborhood to come up with any and all ideas for ways
to address some of the issues we had collected in those six categories. At the start, we did brief introductions and then our ride lead 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/michellecohrene&quot;&gt;Michelle&lt;/a&gt; and our volunteer ride mechanic Brian Fanelli from &lt;a href=&quot;http://morethanabicycle.com/recoverybikeshop.html&quot;&gt;Recovery Bike Shop&lt;/a&gt; 
explained the rules for the ride. 
Then the group set off to the first stop, at the green 
institute building off of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://midtowngreenway.org/about-the-greenway/&quot;&gt;Greenway&lt;/a&gt;. At this stop, we split into groups and each 
took a barrier written on an index card, and we took 10 
minutes to brainstorm hacks to solve the issue on the card. The two categories we did at this stop were hacking the bike and hacking clothing.&lt;/br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, the group headed to Brackett Park, where we thought about hacking the environment and hacking navigation. Then onto the last 
stop at the Hack Factory, where we discussed hacking the cyclist and the culture. Throughout the evening we had some great (and some crazy) 
ideas and discussions. We talked about what it means for an intersection to be &amp;quot;good&amp;quot; for cyclists, how to keep from getting sweaty on 
your way to work, some of the current cycling infrastructure efforts in the neighborhood, and tons of other things.
One of my favorites was in the conversation about hacking the culture, and the problem that drivers seem to hate cyclists (and vice versa!). 
We recalled the idea of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.citylab.com/commute/2015/02/dont-say-cyclists-say-people-on-bikes/385387/&quot;&gt;reframing how we talk about 
cyclists to &amp;quot;people on bikes&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;
 and drivers to &amp;quot;people in cars&amp;quot;, because it leads to a more civil debate, but also because here in Minneapolis, often people go back and forth 
between the two. We also talked about who identifies as a cyclist (kids, hipsters, lyrca dudes) and how it would be great to widen that to 
include all people who ride their bikes, independent of how much or how little they ride, what they wear, who they associate with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/ideation_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ideation Ride start, Greenway&quot;&gt; 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/ideation_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ideation Ride Brackett, Hack Factory&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;First set of photos from the start of the ride by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/robfargo&quot;&gt;Rob Davis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bike Demos&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the attendees, Rachel, brought two bikes she had hacked before CycleHack to demonstrate. One was a backwards steering bike, and the other 
was a swing bike. Some of us tried out the swing bike!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/swing_bike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The swing bike&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of hack day, we heard from Jason Tanzman at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cyclesforchange.org/&quot;&gt;Cycles for Change&lt;/a&gt;, a community bike shop in St. Paul
working to to build a diverse and empowered community of bicyclists. They recently merged with &lt;a href=&quot;http://spokesconnect.org/&quot;&gt;SPOKES Bike Walk Connect&lt;/a&gt;, 
a similar organization in the Seward neighborhood working on the goal of getting more people biking and walking. 
Our ideation ride went past SPOKES, and its founder &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sheldonM&quot;&gt;Sheldon Mains&lt;/a&gt; was on the ride, sharing his hyper-local knowledge 
of activities and infrastructure initiatives that are going on right now. Both Cycles for Change and SPOKES have been working to reduce 
barriers to cycling in the Twin Cities, and it was great that they could be involved with CycleHack. The Twin Cities has a vibrant cycling community 
with many types of interests in improving the cycling experience here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/jason_c4c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jason from Cycles for Change&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jason Tanzman from Cycles for Change, photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jmkeuning&quot;&gt;James Keuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversations, the projects, the people, our supporters, everything about CycleHack was incredibly inspiring and I think provided a unique 
addition to the existing efforts to improve cycling. After months of planning (that should have started much earlier than it did), 
it was really great to see everything come together and to see people so excited and invested in the spirit of the event. I hope that this hack day 
connected people to this amazing place we all live in and to each other. I also hope that the conversations and ideas we had were just
the beginning of an ongoing discussion to keep thinking up innovative ways to make things better and easier for people on bikes (which we now 
call POBs) here in the Twin Cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CycleHack Twin Cities couldn&amp;#39;t have happened without the generous support of our sponsors, so thanks very much to all sponsors and partners! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cyclehacktc_2015/sponsors.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CycleHack Sponsors&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/cre8ivecubed&quot;&gt;Kelly Clausen&lt;/a&gt; at Hennepin County and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/wbushey&quot;&gt;Bill Bushey&lt;/a&gt; at 
Open Twin Cities for their unwavering support (and Costco memberships).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, mad props to the organizing team:&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LKPuffer&quot;&gt;Leah Puffer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zzolo&quot;&gt;Alan Palazzolo&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jmkeuning&quot;&gt;James Keuning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LA0811&quot;&gt;Laura Anderson&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/roxLjohnson&quot;&gt;myself&lt;/a&gt;.
We did it, you guys!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/community/2015/06/29/cyclehack.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/community/2015/06/29/cyclehack.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>community</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PyLadies: Cooking Code for Breakfast</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You may recall that myself and PyLady friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/CaroleJesse?lang=en&quot;&gt;Carole&lt;/a&gt; organized a &lt;a href=&quot;/community/2014/12/11/pyladies-beginner-cohort.html&quot;&gt;beginner cohort&lt;/a&gt; to go through Coursera classes on Python in late 2014. We didn’t stop there! Our other organizers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DanaKE?lang=en&quot;&gt;Dana&lt;/a&gt;, Moni, and later &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/michellecohrene?lang=en&quot;&gt;Michelle&lt;/a&gt; joined in and we renamed our meetups to “Cooking Code for Breakfast”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We continued our cohort into the spring/summer, but without a specific class. Ladies just came to work and to share, and just hang out. I am really proud of all the ladies in our group, we are amazing! I got to spend &lt;a href=&quot;http://parksandrecreation.wikia.com/wiki/Galentine&amp;#x27;s_Day_(event)&quot;&gt;Galentine’s day&lt;/a&gt; with them! I made a digital PyLadies Galentine using Python in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeskulptor.org/&quot;&gt;CodeSkulptor&lt;/a&gt; and the skills I learned in the interactive gaming class. Here&amp;#39;s a link to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.codeskulptor.org/#user39_VKNSWzpQqC_1.py&quot;&gt;the code&lt;/a&gt; on CodeSkulptor and to my &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/2015/02/13/pyladies_galentine.html&quot;&gt;project post&lt;/a&gt; about the Galentine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also super excited to spend the Pi Day of the century (3/14/15) with them all at Seward Co-op.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/2015/pi-day-2015-pyladies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;PyLadies on Pi Day of the Century&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/DanaKE?lang=en&quot;&gt;Dana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March, we branched out a little when Jackie started RLadies. We decided to jointly call ourselves PyRUs, and host joint events at the PybRary- our library, coworking, and meeting space. There are several of us who work with data and are interested in both Python and R, so it seemed to make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO MUCH FUN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/PyLadiesTC/&quot;&gt;PyLadiesTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/RLadiesTC/&quot;&gt;RLadies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/community/2015/05/09/pyladies-cooking-code.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/community/2015/05/09/pyladies-cooking-code.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>community</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CodeWork Unconference</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Unconference principles always tell you that the people who come are the right people. That has never felt more true
than at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://umncodework.github.io/&quot;&gt;CodeWork Unconference&lt;/a&gt; I went to today. The event was organized by some folks at the University of Minnesota&amp;#39;s
Institute for Advanced Study and drew people interested in discussing how code shapes our lives. These people were also interested 
in classics, rhetoric, code, data, ethics, virtual reality, privacy, comics, and even lichen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started the day with some background from the organizers and introductions, and then went right into the first session where 
I got to try out a Raspberry Pi with a camera module. I had previously only played &lt;a href=&quot;https://inventwithpython.com/pygame/chapter8.html&quot;&gt;Squirrel Eat Squirrel&lt;/a&gt; (a game written in Python, BTW) and 
unsuccessfully tried Minecraft. I gave up after falling in some water and didn&amp;#39;t really see the appeal of the game, probably because 
I&amp;#39;m old. We also played with some code that searched for tweets and printed them to a little board, which was pretty rad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we went into our second session, where I got to talk about my favorite subject of late: data analysis in Python. I shared 
about my adventure trying to learn and some &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/PyLadiesTC/Dcubed-installfest-2015/blob/master/resources.md&quot;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; I find really helpful, which led into a fantastic discussion about learning to program, 
the sort of mysticism around &amp;quot;coding&amp;quot;, and the uselessness of stating that you &amp;quot;just need to learn to code&amp;quot;. One of my favorite parts of the 
conversation was around the difference between identifying as a &amp;quot;programmer&amp;quot; or &amp;quot;developer&amp;quot; and the framework of using something like 
Python as one of may tools to accomplish a task or solve a problem. This really got at why I felt like I didn&amp;#39;t really fit in at PyCon 
last week! We were going to talk about citizen science as well but sadly didn&amp;#39;t get to it; we definitely need to do this again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third session I spent talking video games and trying out the Samsung Gear headset, which took each of us flying over... Iceland? Somewhere with 
beautiful waterfalls and vast expanses. I also went in some spaceship thing. We talked about video game worlds and how the player/user has to 
figure out what kind of world they&amp;#39;re in, like in any other story except more immersive. We had talked about some of my favorite stories at lunch 
(like Sophie&amp;#39;s World and the Neverending Story) that either break the fourth wall or otherwise have characters that in some way start 
to question and figure out their place inside the world in which the story takes place. In virtual reality, you have to navigate both the world 
that you enter and see while inside while remaining physically somewhere else, where you can bump into things or fall. We laughed about 
how we can end up in different parts of the room and be completely surprised by this when we emerge from that other world by removing 
the headset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also talked about diversity in game making, and the different stories that can be told when everyone makes games. I brought up one of my 
favorite games, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tamponrun.com/&quot;&gt;Tampon Run&lt;/a&gt;, a game created by a couple high school girls that were sick of the stigma against menstruating women&amp;#39;s bodies. 
they are two of my favorite heroes. In the game you throw tampons at the bad guys. They acknowledge that while the concept of the game may be strange that it&amp;#39;s more strange 
that we accept violence in video games and yet can&amp;#39;t talk about periods. #truth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just when you think it can&amp;#39;t get any better, I met a woman who shares my love of lichen, a guy who recommended the book &lt;a href=&quot;http://catalog.sevenstories.com/products/rise-of-the-videogame&quot;&gt;The Rise of the 
Video Game Zinesters&lt;/a&gt; (which I bought immediately on Amazon) as well as the MCTC zine collection, 
I learned about a hyperlocal independent movie theater, and I geeked out about bags and notebooks and why everything out there is somehow lacking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You guys, these are my people. I can&amp;#39;t wait til the next thing they do! It&amp;#39;s so.much.fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/community/2015/04/18/CodeWork.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/community/2015/04/18/CodeWork.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>community</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>YQdio Book Club: The Beauty Myth</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally made it to the YQdio! I&amp;#39;ve been meaning to go to something since I first tried a Yoga Quest
last summer. If you haven&amp;#39;t done a quest with these folks before, the way it works is that there is a script
based on a movie or episode of a tv show and the characters each have yoga poses associated with them, which
you learn before the quest. Whenever the quest leader says the name of a character, you do their pose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The script I did last summer was for the Star Trek (original series) episode Mirror, Mirror- also known as
the one where evil Spock has a goatee and Uhura wears a midriff shirt (those abs!!). It was absolute hilarity
and I&amp;#39;ve been meaning to go back ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally made it to the actual studio for a feminist book club where we read The Beauty Myth:  How Images of Beauty Are Used Against
Women by Naomi Wolf. In this club meeting we talked about the first half-ish of the book, through the Culture
chapter. The people who went were delightful; in the intros we were asked to share a fun fact and it turned
into a conversation about our childhood toys and interesting ways that we played with them (mine was stop motion
Star Trek; there was other stop motion animation, some lesbian Barbies, fan fiction horses, and
lots and lots of pez dispensers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conversation opened with a discussion about the book being a summarized version of the academic
literature that really seemed to speak to people already onboard with the message. It was written in 1991
so we also talked about ways that the content is dated (pre-internet! before terms like man-scape!). Some 
of us had issues with the citations, others with the tone. Some thought it was dry, some thought it was
pretentious. At some point we had a conversation about &amp;quot;4th wave&amp;quot; feminism which I related to because I
found this 3rd wave book very foreign-feeling, even though I was around (I was 10) when it came out and I think
of many of my friends as 3rd wave. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some highlights of what I took away from the conversation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Work Chapter. What does it mean to look &amp;quot;professional&amp;quot;? What differences in interactions do we experience based on our decisions
of what we wear? Examples: deciding not to wear makeup to a meeting with a client who has hit on you in the past; dressing in a nerd
t-shirt and jeans instead of a dress at a technical conference because you want technical conversations and not just to get hit
on; wearing a wedding ring for the same reason. What difference in interactions do we experience based on what we look like?
Examples: not getting hit on while wearing a dress at a technical conference because maybe you aren&amp;#39;t as &amp;quot;conventionally attractive&amp;quot;;
approachability and &amp;quot;resting bitch face&amp;quot;; not perceiving discrimination because of looking female; perceiving that people don&amp;#39;t take 
you seriously because you&amp;#39;re short, young, queer, fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also talked about ways to respond when a male colleague tells you to smile. I liked the suggestion to redirect and say, &amp;quot;I&amp;#39;m all out of smiles, but try 
[male coworker&amp;#39;s name] over there, I think he has some!&amp;quot;. What I like about it is that if a guy just says this out of habit and not malicious intent 
(which I like to think is the reason most dudes say this kind of stuff) and has never
thought about how women might not appreciate it, it doesn&amp;#39;t humiliate him- it just asks him to think about his action in a way he hasn&amp;#39;t before. 
We had a whole conversation about how for learning to happen and for behavior to change that it needs to be 
okay to make mistakes and it helps when people can talk about it with each other- especially across gender lines.
 I&amp;#39;ve been having this conversation since PyCon! (That&amp;#39;s another post)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Culture Chapter. The book talks a lot about the feminism in Women&amp;#39;s magazines, which I thought was a little foreign to me so I instead thought 
about Pinterest, Facebook, and ad algorithms. They recommend things to users based on all kinds of input, and what is that doing to our perception
of beauty? Another person talked about Fan Fiction and how it was interesting that so many women write about male characters, which led 
to a conversation about how male characters are relatable because they are actual people, with flaws and character, not just plot devices.
I have never read FanFic but I thought it was really interesting when someone said that fanfic allows us to create transformative works, giving an 
example of a gender-swapped Sherlock who amazingly as a woman can be just as much a culturally-accepted asshole. That&amp;#39;s revolutionary!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/community/2015/04/16/yqdio-bookclub.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/community/2015/04/16/yqdio-bookclub.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>community</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
